VALERIIA SHESTAKOVA

Software Engineer

with around five years of production experience in Python development, I specialize in building asynchronous web applications, working with relational and NoSQL databases, and designing microservice architectures. My expertise extends to the AWS stack, CI/CD processes, and Git workflows. As a team player, I contributed to architectural design, worked in Agile environments and participated in onboarding and interview processes.

EXPERIENCE

2023 - present

Senior Software Engineer, Novakid Inc

Remote

Novakid is an online English learning platform that provides interactive lessons for children.

- Optimized API endpoints response time from 5000 ms to 80 ms
- · Owned and enhanced the service by developing new features with WhatsApp integration
- Developed and designed new features using OpenAI / ChatGPT
- Developed plenty of WhatsApp bots using AWS stack [Step functions, Lambdas]

Flask / Pyramid / Python3 / PostgreSQL / AWS SQS/SNS / AWS Step functions / AWS Lambdas / AWS DynamoDB / pytest / Docker / Jenkins / Bitbucket / Kanban

2019 - 2023

Senior Software Engineer, EPAM Systems

Montenegro

The product is a web service for load testing video services developed for telecommunication company

- Lead Back-End team, including interviewing and onboarding newcomers, tasks decomposition, regularly took part in architecture design activities
- · Developed and designed web-handlers logic using FastAPI, aiohttp and asyncio libraries
- Developed and processed ElasticSearch aggregation and PostgreSQL queries with a different complexity
- Run services on AWS using Jenkins pipelines and checking instances states using AWS API, worked with AWS Cost Explorer

FastAPI / Python3 / Tortoise / aiohttp / PostgreSQL / RabbitMQ / ElasticSearch / Kafka / Redis / AWS / Docker / Nomad / pytest / GitLab / Agile

2020 - 2021

Software Engineer, EPAM Systems

Saint Petersburg

The product is a web service for batch document processing developed for pharmaceutical company

- · Worked on a new service development from scratch to the first production release
- Setup and launch web services on AWS servers using Lambda and Step functions
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Integrated developed service with ElasticSearch and performed queries, proceed database queries for DynamoDB

Flask / Python3.7 / AWS Lambda / DynamoDB / ElasticSearch Jenkins / pytest / Bitbucket / AWS Step Functions

EDUCATION

2018 Python course, EPAM Systems

Saint Petersburg

During the course, all main Python topics have been learnt and put into practice. Developed a web service for getting some statistics from external API and displaying it in graphs view. Python3 / Flask

2014 - 2020

Bachelor/Master's Degrees in Software Engineering, ITMO University

Saint Petersburg

The final project was a web service for saving educational results based on Blockchain technology. Python3 / Django / SQLite

CONTACTS



valeriiashestakova@gmail.com



@lerushe

LANGUAGES

Russian

English



